MARCOS SOARES

User Experience Designer & Researcher

I'm a User Experience Designer and Researcher with four years experience and specialising in the user experience of Artificial Intelligence and symbiotic relationships with intelligent machines. I completed my masters degree at the University of Porto, specialising in Human-Computer Interaction and User Experience Research and I'm currently finishing my PhD in Innovation Design Engineering at the Royal College of Art.

Prior to joining the Royal College of Art, I worked at Fraunhofer AICOS and Microsoft Research where I had the opportunity to be an integral part of numerous applied research projects ranging from cultural databases to biological computational systems.

In my free time, you can find me drawing, running or reading science fiction works and history books.

Experience

User Experience Researcher Oddschecker London, United Kingdom October 2019 - Present

At Oddschecker, I'm responsible for all the qualitative and quantitative user experience research for the UK products. My tasks include **strategising user research methodologies**, **generating foundational insights**, **conducting exploratory and evaluative research tasks** such as comparative analysis and usability testing, and **present the results to stakeholders**.

Visiting Lecturer Royal College of Art London, United Kingdom January 2018 - January 2019

As a Visiting Lecturer for the Royal College of Art, I was responsible for providing guidance in the fields of **Design Research**, **Human Computer Interaction** and **Artificial Intelligence** to the students enrolled in the Master of Research programmes. I was also in charge of presenting and organising discussions around the topics of transhumanism, Human Computer Interaction and Artificial Intelligence.

Research Intern Microsoft Research Cambridge, United Kingdom June 2017 - September 2017

For the duration of three months, I was a member of both the **Biological Computation Group** and the **Human Experience Design (HxD) Group** at Microsoft Research. My tasks were situated in the disciplines of Visual Design and Interaction Design and I was the only research intern in the group with a Design and Human-computer Interaction background. I was responsible for **conducting user research, analyse data, create design artefacts, build prototypes** and **validate design solutions** for the Biological Computation Group.

Contact Details

Based in

London, United Kingdom

F-mail

marcos.barroso.soares@gmail.com

Telephone **07473 251060**

Skype

soares.marcos.andre

Portfolio

behance.net/soaresdesigns

Github

github.com/marcosandresoares

Previous Areas of Research

Cultural Databases

Data Collection in remote and underserved areas

Fall Monitoring and Prevention

Exergaming

Food Recommendation Systems

mHealth Solutions

Biological Computational Systems

Human-Al Interaction

User Experience / Human-Computer Interaction Scientist Fraunhofer Portugal Porto, Portugal May 2016 - September 2016

As a member of the Human Computer interaction team, my responsibilities include conducting user research and gather user insights in order to design appropriate solutions for the target audience. I was responsible for analysing data and deliver design artefacts and deliverables related to a number of projects. As a scientist at Fraunhofer Portugal, I had the opportunity to work in projects related to: Nutrition and Nutrition Education, Fall Risk Assessment and Fall Monitoring.

User Experience Researcher Fraunhofer Portugal Porto, Portugal October 2014 - April 2016

As a member of the Human Computer interaction team, I worked for the ICT4D Competence Center and the AAL Competence Center. My responsibilities included conducting user research and gathering user insights in order to design appropriate solutions for the target audience. I was responsible for analysing data and deliver design artefacts and deliverables related to a number of projects. As a researcher at Fraunhofer Portugal, I had the opportunity to work in projects related to: ICT4D (Information and Communication Technologies for development), Cultural Databases, Remote User Research Methods for developing countries, Activity Monitoring, Food Logging Techniques, Nutrition and Nutrition Education.

Expertise

Interaction Design

UX Design Research

Survey Research

Design Strategy

Data Analysis

Statistical Methods

Interviewing

Usability Testing

Project Management

Prototyping

User Interface Design

Education

PhD in Innovation Design Engineering Royal College of Art United Kingdom September 2016 - Present

Masters in Multimedia - Specialization in Technologies Faculdade de Engenharia da Universidade do Porto Portugal September 2013 - July 2015

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Art State University of New York College at Oneonta United States of America January 2009 - December 2011

Bachelor's Degree in Anthropology State University of New York College at Oneonta United States of America January 2009 - December 2011

Software & Programming

Adobe Suite

Sketch

Microsoft Office

Figma

Python

HTML5 & CSS3

Javascript

R